# **Todd Oh**

email: toddstonefieldoh@gmail.com | phone: 917-609-9314 | website: toddoh.com | location: New York, NY

## **OVERVIEW**

I'm a full-stack web developer with diverse experience across product development in the startup industry. The projects I have worked on over the years are connected with interactive content, data analytics, news aggregation, and web applications. Formerly an Engineering Lead at a startup company, I gained expertise in developing production-level products from launching a news briefing service at the University of Pennsylvania.

With my expertise in products and engineering practices, I can contribute to creating quality software and product strategy.

#### **SKILLS**

**Frontend** — Javascript/Node.js expert, CSS, HTML DOM manipulation/ optimization, React.js, react-redux, lithtml, Handlebars.js.

**Backend** — Production-level RESTful API and database architecting experiences, MongoDB, MySQL, Linux/ AWS EC2 Server.

**Python 3** — Data Aggregation, Natural Language Processing with nltk/spaCy, LDA Modeling, K-Means Clustering, Flask

**UI Design** — Designed a number of production applications using Sketch, Figma

**Tools** — Git, Sentry.io, Mixpanel, Mailchimp, SparkPost, OneSignal, Google Analytics, Facebook Ads **Languages** — Full proficiency in English and Korean, Localization

#### **WEBSITE**

### Github profile

https://github.com/toddoh/

### Portfolio website

https://toddoh.com

### **EDUCATION**

## B.S. Sociology, 2018

Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Data Visualization Engineer, THISISALLABOUT**

Oct 2017 - Present | New York, NY

Led early-stage engineering at this data-driven journalism project. Built an automatic news clustering system to visualize complex issues and agendas by group, timeframe, and topic.

Designed and developed original visualization contents, including "WhatTrumpSaid", to analyze over 10k tweets by President Trump and key presidential candidates, enabling people to read through the agendas across time.

- Implemented natural text processing with Tf-ldf/word2doc, and K-Means clustering for automatic daily news clustering.
- Created an original analysis of the historical tweets of key presidential candidates and President Trump using Doc2bow corpus/LDA/K-Means clustering/ Vectorization in Python.
- Built an in-house dataset editor console with Node.js, MongoDB, React.js.
- Managed a Facebook page to promote content.

# Engineering Lead/Founder, Toast Labs, LLC.

Apr 2015 - Jul 2017 | Palo Alto, CA

Led a technology startup that developed and launched mobile applications, including "#Newsrooms", which provided a solution for journalistic bias by an news briefing generated automatically.

Built a custom frontend framework for the applications and news natural language processing backend in Node.js. Oversaw product strategy and engineering process.

- Built a custom frontend framework in JavaScript.
- Built a Node.js/MongoDB server running a number of API endpoints and natural language processing for a news aggregation service "#Newsrooms".
- Managed Mixpanel analytics to improve user retention and discoverability, in conjunction with data-driven interface redesign.
- Built an adaptive low-power geofence engine and camera scribble experience in Objective-C.
- Designed user interface for multiple applications.

### Intern, Ars Praxia (TREUM)

Nov 2011 - Feb 2012 | Seoul, South Korea

Helped the team to perform data cleaning for a Semantic Network Analysis project. Built the original company website.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Samsung Electronics Super Rookie Membership** — An invite-only program for students in STEM and Liberal Arts (2012-2013)

**Startupweekend 2010 Seoul** — Member of an organizing group for the event. **TEDxYouth Seoul 2010** — Gave a speech about global startup experience.